They appear at the time of neural tube closure.
It's something that runs along the neural groove.
It’s something, if you will, that occurs all along.
These are the invaders.
They will truly give rise to the entire peripheral nervous system.
So everything consists of nerves, it’s all ganglionic chains,
just from a neurological standpoint, already.
This is neural crest. At the head level, it
will really have a
invasion, a practically migration, the neural crests that are there
and that
will truly come and give a large portion
of the whole face,
from bone to skin level. We can see in humans at the
base
of the skull. You see how it is really a tissue that
not only mixes but
organizes with the mesoderm.
It becomes what we call ectomesenchyme.
Here, we can really see, you see, this migration, this invasion,
you see,
with the rhombomeres, you see, for example, with the area, we could
say, rhombencephalic,
which will organize all around at the level of the optic capsule, etc.
All the mesencephalic area
too, which is sub-optic, here, like this.
Then you have all the rhombomere 1,
so the rhombomeres,
that we will divide from 1
to 7, which will
invade the superior pharyngeal arch,
median,
inferior, etc.
So all this,
ultimately, up to here,
is the cream.
It’s a tissue that is informed,
strongly by the nervous system.
So that means
that your skin, here, it’s a
nervous tissue more than
your fingers. I mean it’s super
informed. And it is informed by
scelactic radiation,
by pressures,
by behavior.
And on the face, we can read
a lot about the face.
The entire ganglionic chain,
the entire pre-visceral chain,
all the ganglia, one
all this comes from this
neural crest. It will also have
a significant action
on your entire sympathetic nervous system
and parasympathetic.
All this,
is information that affects
both the heart, the lungs,
the parotid glands,
the submandibulars, the eye,
the digestive tubes, all this is information
that can be
read on the face. So everything here,
via neural crest formation
can express itself externally.
That’s why when looking at a face,
you can start to express,
to see how a stomach is doing,
how a kidney is doing,
how your internal state is.
Because it expresses itself that way.
It’s a reading.
You see here, for example,
that the quality of the skin,
is expressed through these dorsal ganglia,
ganglionic and these filaments
even at the level
of your adrenal glands
and all your enteric plexus.
Your entire digestive system
integrates and informs you.
You see?
This link. We see here how this migration
occurs from this humerus
and it will follow.
You directly jump
the epithelial type tissue
neurological to form your chain
of ganglia or else participate
in others, with connections, integrins, laminins,
they're simply connections to foster melatonin.
The trigeminal nerves, 5,
the trigeminals arise from this concentration,
with the different, all the cranial nerves,
which we will see and position in a way with an
important branch,
of 10, here, which will give all the visceral information,
up to the level, here, behind,
with your stomach, the wave, all cranial distribution, with
large entities, which we
will work on shortly, called the archeocranium, paleocranium, neurocranium,
this is... all this are...
information carried by the neural crest.
This migration of the neural crest,
to form your trigeminal nerve, for example,
will depend on this trigeminal ganglion,
and this field will be formed between the optical placode,
nasal and optic.
The trigeminal is the result of three converging fields
that are induced by the dural sheaths
that we will study shortly.
which will actually follow the information of the meninges at a given time
in their developmental path.
We see all the information from Silver Request, you see, which will yield all
this information
up to the level of the earlobes, the eyes, etc.
Look at everything it touches.
Look at all the cascade development here.
All this is epigenetic.
of this neural crest which gives this information.
The inner ear too, it’s still important to see
everything it will touch at the cartilaginous level,
at the bony level or at the level of your system here.
The eye, all its migratory phase
that will be dependent on this neural crest
will completely
position itself finally
at the level of the cornea part
and the placode here
which provides continuity
both neurologically
and facially
of mesodermal type.
The eye is related
to the entirety of the heart.
All the phases of signaling
on the levels
of bone morphogenetic
of all these genes that will
on a chart.
On the genetic level.
I’m interested in this now, because if I begin to understand what it means,
before I didn’t understand, I don’t see them as completely silly names anymore.
It's true, because the FTI CEO is Alpha,
and what interests me is seeing the processes of differentiation,
remodeling, proliferation, migration, delimitation, specialization.
It’s a whole magical cascade like this in the body,
but here, we are on purely molecular levels.
It’s yet another level, but at the same time, what you do
automatically impacts that, even if you don’t fully understand what you are really doing.
That's why it's interesting to study it once, to see it once,
because it shows that epigenetics is here. Here, it's a bit of specific lines
that it takes.
A well-directed signaling.
The same thing at the level of your face, with neural crests
that are of purely mesodermal origin.
Finally, it's the only mesodermal link, but it's the only purely neurological link,
with specific invasions in the forebrain, big brain, high brain.
The same applies to everything it will touch in the sympathetic, parasympathetic systems.
All this is neural crest.
Let’s go!
No, we forget that one.
The base of the skull will mainly derive from para-axial mesenchyme,
while the base
of the dental arches will mainly derive from the neural crest.
The vertebral column derives from the ribs of mesenchyme.
and the skeleton of the limbs derives from the somatopleure which forms the limbs.
What does that mean for you?
It already gives us three accesses, three frequencies we need to work on.
It means that treating the face or teeth should be done with the original green shades.
Treating the base of the skull, the spine, involves homologous treatment
in relation to...
the origin
That is to say that treating a house
of limbs implies reclaiming
the territory.
And thus,
to treat a limb, it's about reintegrating it into the cavity
On a pulmonary level.
We will seek
a support point at the level of the lung.
We move to the next time.
You will just...
We will simply look for the articulation point between the
parietal peritoneum and the visceral peritoneum.
Which is just a meeting point at the level of the pulmonary hilum.
It’s
where I have this articulation.
First, you see where it comes from.
So it comes from...
you set me
it’s really like a suction field
that invades everything,
so I have this knowledge
I have this vision
I can almost see it
I can feel it
we will see it
how it happens at the level of the skull
because you have a migratory field
there at the shoulder
I will show you how I reintegrate it
how I reintegrate it
because it shows us the work to be done, it’s to show you some pathways
for reflection.